Doug Proctor

Lead UX / UI Designer

Hello, I'm a London-based all-round designer with a focus on discovery and strategy. I have particular expertise in IA, prototyping and interaction design, and a broad range of experience that also spans visual design, software engineering, design ops and delivery.

EXPERIENCE

Product designer (contract)

Vipps ID solutions, 9 months (August 2019 — May 2020)

Working with a brand new biometric identification startup, bringing user-centred design to the product development process. As the only designer I took care of UX design, prototyping, user testing, UI design and design system creation.

Co-founder

Livelink, 13 months, (March 2019 — present)

Livelink helps hospitality businesses reduce the cost and increase the returns of their live entertainment programme. Working with my team to develop business and product strategies into a robust design process and technical approach.

Product designer & developer (contract)

Flink Works, 8 months (January — August 2019)

UX, UI & full-stack development of a brand new MVP for a professional networking / social media startup.

Product designer (contract)

OneDome, 2 months (November — December 2018)

Solo end-to-end design for a brand new mortgage application service. This involved intensive proposition validation, then IA and prototype development through guerrilla testing and rapid iteration while moving into a high-fidelity UI phase. Working with engineers to navigate constraints and ensure the smooth delivery of an optimal user experience.

Design Consultant (contract)

iProov, 14 months (May 2017 — July 2018)

This was a hybrid role: product lead, IA & interaction designer, frontend developer. I worked with the CEO to design iProov's business support systems, from their customer support portals, to their sales tools, to their custom SaaS billing system. I supervised delivery and overall fulfilment of the business strategy.

Senior Interaction Designer (contract)

Grey London, 1 month (April — May 2017)

Collaborating with researchers to redefine the business model and service offering for a key internet security brand. Lots of prototyping and testing.

Senior Experience Designer & UX Lead

Engine Group, 11 months (June 2016 — April 2017)

I was responsible for defining, crafting and overseeing the experience design on all digital touch points between E.ON Energy and their customers, from website to mobile app to smart home products, with a team of 3 UX designers, within an ongoing digital transformation programme.

Experience Designer

Engine Group, 7 months (December 2015 — June 2016)

I worked alongside strategy, business analysts, engineers and visual designers to identify requirements, study users, set design goals, and craft experiences that translate business and user needs into highly engaging experiences.

Experience Designer

Isobar, 9 months (March — December 2015)

Worked with a number of high-profile clients in FMCG, automotive and pharmaceutical to help deliver brand websites, activations, product launches and digital experiences.

UX & UI Designer (contract)

Network Locum, 1 month (January — February 2015)

Supported the continued growth of Network Locum by researching the organisational culture of the NHS and iterating on various services and interfaces to improve the viability of the business.

UX Designer

Better Brief, 3 years (May 2011 — November 2014)

Lead the user experience practise, working closely with clients, developers and visual designers.

Software developer

Better Brief, 6 months (May — November 2011)

Created front-end and back-end solutions for a range of clients.

Software designer (freelance)

Various, 5 years (January 2009 — November 2014)

Designed and developed websites and internal business tools for a range of London-based businesses.

SKILLS

- Strategy, collaboration, leadership
- IA & interaction design, experience and journey mapping, design systems, UI design.
- Guerilla testing & validation, formal research methodologies and programmes
- Lo-fi and HTML/JavaScript prototypes, technical feasibility assessments

SOFTWARE

- Figma, Sketch, InVision, Zeplin.io, Framer.js, Marvel, Confluence, JIRA, etc
- HTML, CSS, React / Redux / Saga, Vue.js, Laravel / Lumen, Jamstack

• I also make my own custom software tools for particular jobs and workflows

EDUCATION

B.Soc.Sci (Hons) Political Science, Philosophy & Economics

University of KwaZulu-Natal (South Africa), 2004